We are going to be discussing about Azure Active Directory from your Microsoft 365 admin
center.
We just scroll down here on the admin center as you can see we have the Azure Active Directory.
So let me just click on the Azure Azure Active Directory is part of the Microsoft admin center,
which of course an enterprise identity service that provided single sign-on multi-factor
authentication and conditional access to getting cyber security attack and also you can also
manage your users' groups and more.
So here we have our Azure Active Directory.
If I click on the Azure Active Directory, you can see we have some other teams we can
actually manage from here.
For example, we have our users.
So for example, if I click on users, you can see that most of the users are actually synced
from our own premises environment.
You can see it's on premises, sync enabled, you can see it says all the years, which means
that all these users have been synced from my Active Directory on prem.
But at the same time, I can't decide to actually create a new user.
I can see we can have the created new user or we can find a new user.
So if I just click create new user, you can see we can decide to actually create a new
user or it says invite a guest user to collaborate with your organization.
So here we can decide to enter the user's name and all.
Well mind you, when you create a new user from your Azure Active Directory or from your Microsoft
365 admin center, the user will not be able to log on to your own premises environment.
But every other single user would be synced from your own premises environment.
We will be able to log on to the Office 365 environment and also to your own premises.
So let me just cancel this because I'm not going to create a new user for that and cancel
this as well.
So unless at the same time, you can see we have groups and also the same scenario.
You can see all the security groups also, most of the security group are pronounced from
my own premises, most of the security group is what I actually created here in this environment.
Well, what I actually did, I have to leave, configure the right value that all the security
group is good at the right back again to my own premises environments.
And also if I cancel this, you can see we can't really do more in our Azure Active Directory.
For example, if you're not actually connect your premises to Azure, to Azure configurable,
to have a hybrid environment.
Here we have the Azure Active Directory Connect that is Azure AD Connect, which of course
allows you to actually sync your device with your premises device to the cloud here.
If I click on connecting, you can see since last less than one hour, it goes with me
that my own premises environment is actually being synced to the cloud.
So if I go back again, you can see we also have, for example, so we can actually configure
password reset, we can do our company branding.
And here on our monitoring, we can totally monitor those that are all assigning to Microsoft
365.
For example, if I go to signing logs, here we can see we are actually seeing a lot of
file of those that are logged on, it says which application that are they used to log on
to Office 365.
For example, we have Kelvin Johnson, which I just log on to the Azure portal, portal, and
we have Tomos.
So you can see it says the Windows signing, which means he logs on to its device.
And also you can see we have like Kelvin Johnson has me logging on using Office 365 shell.
And also if I go to audit log, we're going to get some local data that has been recorded
for the past weeks or months here, we have the last one for our website, go to the last seven
days.
Yeah, we can see we have, for example, about the vices and you can see the sources, you can
see when was that device, actually log with the targets, you can see it says the SCCM.
And that was me Kelvin Johnson Windows, I totally secret you go through, you can't only
manage, but I'm monitor the audit, the logs that what I totally took place from your, from
the files and also from your Office 365 file remains.
And if I go to users, I do what I told them for, in the beginning, you can see here
we can totally do a password reset, we can go to users settings, and also we can totally
go to the audit log as well from here to monitor who, which of the user, actually log on
to the Office 365 environment.
So if I go to all service, yeah, you can see we can actually click one of these service
to actually manage it from here, for example, the Azure Active Directory, the Azure AD security,
the Azure AD identity protection, we have multi-fart audit, guitar, we have app proxy and
lots more. So from Azure Active Directory, you should be able to monitor your users, groups,
manage security, multi-fart audit, creation, creates conditional access for your devices, and
lots more.
So next we are going to be discussing about configuration manager.